

Carlos Crisóstomo







CYBERSECURITY



+34 609557351



ccvals@linux.com



Madrid, Spain



https://xift.ai



linkedin.com/in/ccvals



github.com/Kr0n0



EDUCATION

MSc in Artificial Intelligence
UNIR, La Rioja

2018-2020 (Expected)

MSc in Cybersecurity

UNIR, La Rioja 2016-2018 (Not finished)

Computer Engineering Degree

UPSAM, Madrid 2014-2016

MPM (Master of Project Management) PMP - PMBOKv5

CAS Training, Madrid 2014

Technical Engineering in Computer Systems

UPSAM, Madrid 2000-2012

LANGUAGES

English
Fluent
French
Fluent
Spanish

Mother tongue

ABOUT ME

I am an Engineer with more than 25 year-experience in Open Source and GNU/Linux systems. I consider myself a technology enthusiast. During my professional career I have been in continuous learning with different higher education programs, courses and specialization trainings. They have allowed me to move up in heterogeneous fields from cybersecurity to artificial intelligence through a long career in the development of embedded systems.

As a manager I had the opportunity to successfully lead work teams in different locations but today my main value, after more than 4 years as a freelancer and entrepreneur, is my autonomy when it comes to work and my ability to assume responsibilities in decision making.

I like projects that create a technological challenge because technology is my main motivation, keeping up both researching and learning.

EXPERIENCE

2019 - Present Xift

Founder | AI / Infosec / Embedded Systems Engineer #ENTREPRENEUR #AI #INFOSEC #EMBEDDED

2015 – Present Freelance

Embedded Operating Systems Expert
#ENTREPRENEUR #CONSULTANCY #EMBEDDED #INFOSEC

2018 Madrid Internet of Things Institute (MIOTI)

Associate Professor #TEACHING #INFOSEC

2015-2017 EthelHub

CEO / Founder
#ENTREPRENEUR #INFOSEC #EMBEDDED

2012-2015 Arteche Smart Grid

Operating Systems D&D Dept. Manager / Project Manager #EMBEDDED #MANAGEMENT #INFOSEC

2011-2012 Sistemas Avanzados de Control

Head of Operating Systems D&D / Project Manager #EMBEDDED #MANAGEMENT

SKILLS

Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Pentesting / Ethical Hacking

Reverse Engineering

Operating Systems D&D

Hardware

Project Management (PMP)

Agile Project Management (SCRUM)

COURSES

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning with TensorFlow on Google Cloud Platform Specialization (Google Cloud, Coursera)

Machine Learning (Standford University, Coursera)

Cybersecurity

Cyberwar - Advanced Offensive Cyber Operations (StrategicSec)

DFIR in iOS/Android (Securizame)

Practical Ethical Hacking Training (Securizame)

Embedded Systems

Intro to Zynq Architecture with Vivado HDL (Xilinx)

Embedded Linux OS design under ARM9 platform (Atmel)

Real-time OS design (ULMA)

Management

SCRUM Master Training and Certification (Xsfera)

Fundamentals of Marketing (University of Pennsylvania, Coursera)

Lean Startup and Design Thinking (Google Activate)

DevOps

Official Docker Training (Docker)

EXPERIENCE

2008-2011

Sistemas Avanzados de Control

IT Systems Technical Manager / Systems Analyst #SYSADMIN #MANAGEMENT

2010 CICE

Training Collaborator
#TEACHING #SYSADMIN

2006-2009 TNS Global

Technological Expert Panelist Collaborator #CONSULTANCY

2005-2008 Unisys Consulting

Systems Analyst #SYSADMIN

2005-2008 Telefónica Group
Systems Analyst (TD/TdE/TME)

#SYSADMIN #INFOSEC

2005 Unisys Consulting

Systems Specialist #SYSADMIN

2004 Unisys Consulting

Systems Internship / Grant Holder #SYSADMIN

2000 Join Free Business (JFB)

Junior Developer

PRESENT AND PAST AFFILIATIONS

Project Manager Institute (PMI)

Project Manager Institute (PMI) Madrid, Spain Chapter

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) Spain Section

Linux Foundation (LF)

Free Software Foundation (FSF)

EuropeanScrum.org

OWASP Foundation

OWASP Foundation Madrid, Spain Chapter

Asociación Española de Inteligencia Artificial (AEPIA)

European Al Alliance (European Commision)